I have this problem that the car seems
今起きている問題は
to pull too hard to the left.
車が左に強く引っ張られることです
This actually makes sense.
これは実は理にかなっています
The training track is a loop, and the car
トレーニングトラックはループです
drives counter-clockwise.
車は反時計回りに進みます
So most of the time, the model is
ほとんどの場合
learning to steer to the left.
モデルはハンドルを左に切ることを学習しています
Then in autonomous mode, the model does steer to the left
自律モードでは モデルはまっすぐ進むのが最善の状況でも
even in situations when staying straight might be best.
ハンドルを左に切ります
One approach to mitigate this problem is data augmentation.
この問題を軽減するための1つのアプローチは　データオーグメンテーションです
There are many ways to augment data to expand the training set
データを拡張してトレーニングセットを拡大し
and help the model generalize better.
モデルをより一般化する方法は多数あります
I could change the brightness on the images
画像の明るさを変えたり
or I could shift them horizontally or vertically.
水平方向や垂直方向に移動させたりします
In this case, though, I'm going to keep things pretty simple.
ただしここでは もっとシンプルなことをします
I'm just going to flip the images horizontally
鏡のように画像を
like a mirror.
左右に反転させるのです
Then I'll invert the steering angles,
ステアリング角度を反転し
and I should wind up with a balanced data
最後にデータセットのバランスを取ります
set that teaches the car to steer clockwise, as well
これにより車は 反時計回りと同様に
as counter-clockwise.
時計回りにもハンドルを切れるようになります
Just like with using side camera data, using data augmentation
サイドカメラのデータを使用する場合と同様に
carries two benefits.
データ拡張には2つのメリットがあります
One, we have more data to use for training the network.
1つ目は ネットワークのトレーニングに使用できるデータが増えることです
And two, the data we use for training the network
2つ目は ネットワークのトレーニングに使用できる
is more comprehensive.
データがより包括的になることです
Training seems to be going fine, and I
トレーニングは順調のようです
can see that each epoch is training on about twice
以前の約2倍の数の画像で
as many images as before.
トレーニングされているのを確認できます
That makes sense since I copied each image
各画像をコピーしてそのコピーを反転させたので
and then flipped the copy.
倍の数になりました
Let's see how this model does.
モデルはどうなったでしょうか
Even better.
よくなりました
There's still a long way to go, but it
まだ道のりは長いですが
feels like the model is making progress.
確実に進歩しているようです